

VARJE KASS

Software Developer

ABOUT ME

I started studying programming in 2015 and have been working as a developer since 2017. Programming world is fascinating for me as it is in constant change.

In my free time, I enjoy dancing, board games, DIY projects and doing volunteer work — either connected to Estonian folklore, mentally challenged people, or animals.

I am open to new projects and work offers. Work location should preferably be in Tartu, Estonia or remote. For me work is not only salary, but I would like to find something that I really believe in and love to develop.

I speak Estonian and English fluently and a bit of French and Russian.

CONTACT

EMAIL:

varjekass@gmail.com

PHONE:

+372 59 03 96 97

WEBSITE:

varje.github.io

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/varje-kass

EDUCATION

Tartu Vocational Education Centre

2016 - 2018

Specialty: junior software developer (web specialist)

Professional standards: ISCO 2519; ISCED: 0613; EMTAK: 62

Dissertation: Web-application for creating and evaluating

personalized recommendations

University of Tartu

2012 - 2016

Specialty: Biology, BSc

Dissertation: Protein Mgm101 and its deletion impact on the

stability of mitochondrial DNA: graded "A"

WORK EXPERIENCE

Skype Technologies OÜ - Software engineer

March 2019 - April 2020

I worked with discovering and preventing fraud cases on project connected to Bing ads and Skype numbers added to them.

Main tools: Python, PHP, PostgreSQL

STACC OÜ – Software Developer

April 2017-March 2019

Working with different projects for private and public sector. During my worktime, I gained experience with creating designs and mockups, doing front-end and back-end development, testing, data visualization and task management.

Main tools: Python, JavaScript, Git, Django, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, Moqups

Non-software work experience

Baltmi AS – Encoder, March 2016–April 2017 University of Tartu – Microbiologist internship, Oct 2013–May 2016 McCafe; Coffee IN OÜ – barista, May 2011-September 2013 Other jobs – mailman; berry selling, packaging, picking; summers

SKILLS

